BROWN UNIVERSITY

Placement Director: Toru Kitagawa toru_kitagawa@brown.edu 401-863-3688 Graduate Administrator: Angelica Spertini angelica_spertini@brown.edu 401-863-2465

Office Contact Information

Department of Economics, Box B Brown University Providence, Rhode Island 02912 phone: +1 (202) 9078734

References

Professor Andrew Foster
Department of Economics, Box B
Brown University
Providence, Rhode Island 02912
afoster@brown.edu

Professor Bryce Steinberg
Department of Economics, Box B
Brown University
Providence, Rhode Island 02912
bryce_steinberg@brown.edu

Professor Neil Thakral
Department of Economics, Box B
Brown University
Providence, Rhode Island 02912
neil_thakral@brown.edu

Job Market Paper

Free Childcare and the Motherhood Penalty: Evidence from São Paulo

with Marcela Mello and Rafael Latham-Proença

Latin America consistently has some of the world's largest child penalties (or motherhood penalties) for women, and while subsidized childcare is often advanced as a remedy, the literature on its effectiveness is scarce outside developed countries. This paper estimates the impact of a rapid expansion of public childcare on mothers' careers in the city of São Paulo. We leverage the precise location and timing of the expansion of childcare facilities, coupled with detailed data on the labor market and household characteristics to identify effects on mothers' labor market participation and earnings. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we compare the child penalty in districts that experienced a large and rapid expansion of childcare with districts with no significant expansion. Our results show that an additional seat per child leads to an increase of 6.4 p.p. (20%) in the mothers' formal employment after the first child's birth. We do not detect any effect of this expansion on two comparison groups: mothers-to-be and fathers.

Working Papers

Optimizing Incentives for Solar: Accounting for Regional Differences in Emissions

Child Disability and Mothers' Work: Evidence from the Zika Virus Outbreak With Marcela Mello and Rafael Latham-Proença

Teaching

- Teaching excellence award in 2021
- Brown Graduate: Macroeconomics, Econometrics
- Brown MPA: Microeconomics, Statistics, Econometrics, Public Policy
- Brown Undergraduate: Environmental Economics, Public Economics

EDUCATION

Brown University	Providence, RI, USA
Ph.D. Candidate in Economics	2018 -May 2024 (Expected)

Fundacao Getulio Vargas	Sao Paulo, Brazil
M.A. Economics	2015 - 2015

University of Sao Paulo	Sao Paulo, Brazil
B.A. Economics	2012 - 2013

Work Experience

- Research Assistant: Professor David Weil (2018–2019)
- Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant: Professors Dave Donaldson, Dina Pomeranz, Monica Singhal and Paul Carrillo (2016–2017)
- Summer Internship: Wayfair Inc. (2022)

OTHER

- Nationality: Brazilian
- Languages: Fluent English, Native Portuguese, Advanced Spanish
- Conferences: NEUDC 2022; Monash Environmental Economics Workshop 2023 (expected December)